Jiacheng Lin

jachingooo@gmail.com | github | <u>CSDN</u>

EDUCATION

B.Eng in Computer Science and Technology

Aug. 2020 – present

Ocean University of China

- Courses: Data Structures and Algorithms, Discrete Mathematics, Computer Networks, Operating Systems
- Interest: AI, Visualization Technology, Software Engineering, Computer Organization Principle
- GPA:3.4 last term
- IELTS:7.0

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

Experimental Project

Sep. 2020 – Present

 $advised\ by\ counselor\ Xue$

• Machine Learning

[ResNet] Gesture Recognition Using ModelArts

-creating datasets, developing training in algorithms, converting training into skill and deploying and executing tasks online

• Human-Computer Interaction

[JetBot] Target Tracking and Obstacle Avoidance of Robot Vehicles

-embedded hardware and wireless signal connection, embedded programming with ROS, and image recognition training and detection

• Data Analysis and Visualization

Visualizing Data in a Practical Scenery Web-building

-data analysis and efficient information collection in healthcare scenery with multiple patients, Python data processing and JSON-storage, building HTML webpages with data-binding and CSS styling

Lab Research

Jun. 2022 – Present

supervised by professor Cao

• Computer Vision

Optimization of a Semi-Supervised Hash Coding Image Recognition Model

-*con-authoring a paper as currently under submission*

-responsible for code debugging and result recording

• Machine Learning

Reproduction of Classic Models and Data Support

-my responsible par: SDH, TBH, SSDH ...

-proficient in building models and common datasets, and knowledgeable about GPUs

Graduate Student Seminar

Dec. 2021 – Present

guided by professor Cao and professor Yu

• Large-scale Data Retrieval ...

Long-term Participation in Different Fields

- -listening to reports on series topics and engaging in discussion
- -proficient in studying, recording, and presenting research reports

Extracurricular Activities

ByteDance Youth Camp | ByteDance Inc.

- -participant engaged in activities to learn back-end development skills and gained knowledge on its practical applications in commercial development. Fall 2021
- -project leader studied Android client development, gained experience in project coordination, and successfully delivered a project demonstration. Summer 2022

SRDP Project-initiator | Ocean University of China

-responsible for the independent project-proposal.

-select undergraduate self-interest research topic with teammates.

Unpaid Part-time Job in Library | Ocean University of China

- -providing information and consultation services to student.
- -gained a strengthened sense of responsibility and fulfillment.
- -enhanced communication and interpersonal skills.

About Me

 ${\bf Honor}: Received\ college\ encouragement\ scholarship\ for\ three\ consecutive\ semesters.$

Github: Created and participated in projects, as well as personal interests in various fields.

 $\mathbf{CSDN}: Long-term\ professional\ learning\ records\ include\ algorithm\ learning\ and\ experience\ sharing.$

MINOR: Taking some civil engineering core courses at 1st year for interest.